Finding Aid for the W.W. Robinson papers, ca. 1843-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Writings: unpublished.
  - Factual / Historical.
    - The Rise of Los Angeles. 1951.
      - Manuscript material.
        - The rise of Los Angeles., No date (Box 52, Folder 11)
          2 cop. 48 leaves total. Typescript and typescript (carbon). Also notes
        - The rise of Los Angeles., No date (Box 52, Folder 12)
          25 leaves. Typescript (carbon)
        - The rise of Los Angeles., No date (Box 52, Folder 13)
          2 cop. 78 leaves total. Typescript (carbon). One copy lacks title page
        - Chapter 14 - Metropolitan area., No date (Box 52, Folder 14)
          4 leaves. Typescript with extensive holograph corrections and holograph
        - Chapters 1 - 7., No date (Box 52, Folder 15)
          138 [1] leaves. Typescript. Unnumbered leaf is a list: Chapters yet to be written. This copy lacks Chapter 1 (leaf 1 - 14)
        - The rise of Los Angeles., No date (Box 52, Folder 16)
          Another copy. 138 [1] leaves. Typescript (carbon)
        - The rise of Los Angeles., No date (Box 52, Folder 17)
          Another copy. 125 leaves. Typescript (carbon). Lacks chapter one, as typescript above
        - A look at Los Angeles., No date (Box 52, Folder 18)
          2 cop. 30 leaves total. Typescript and typescript (carbon). Seemingly done for separate submission
    - The Springs that Made Palm Springs. After 1959.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., No date (Box 53, Folder 5)
          5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections
    - The Story of J.E. Hoeft.
      - Manuscript material.
        - Correspondence., 1969 (Box 53, Folder 25)
        - Letters from WWR., 1969 Jun (Box 53, Folder 27)
        - The story of J.E. Hoeft., 1969 (Box 53, Folder 28)
      - Research material.
        - WWR's notes., No date (Box 53, Folder 22)
          20 leaves. Holograph
        - Printed brochures., 1967, 1969 (Box 53, Folder 23)
        - Newspaper clippings., 1969 and no date (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - The Story of J.E. Hoeft. 2 Cop.
      - Manuscript material.
        - No title., 1969 (Box 53, Folder 26)
          16 leaves total. Typescript and typescript (carbon)
    - The Story of Valencia, California, and its Rancho Background.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., No date (Box 53, Folder 33)
          30 [3] leaves. Typescript and typescript (carbon). Typescript and carbon typescript with holograph corrections
        - Another typing., No date (Box 53, Folder 34)
          2 cop. 74 leaves total. Typescript (photocopy)
      - Manuscript material.
        - Correspondence., 1967 (Box 53, Folder 32)
          9 items, 11 pcs
      - Research material.
        - WWR's notes., No date (Box 53, Folder 29)
          12 leaves. Typescript and holograph
        - Plat of rancho (photocopy) and del Valle items (typescript copies)., No date (Box 53, Folder 30)
        - Printed promotional brochures and chain of title., No date (Box 53, Folder 31)
    - The Tar Pits of Hancock Park.
      - Manuscript.
        - The tar pits of Hancock Park., No date (Box 51, Folder 46)
          2 leaves. Typescript (carbon). With note from envelope: Wilshire Blvd - Pioneer Sav L. Assn
    - Theology's Heydey [2310 S. Palm Grove Avenue].
      - Manuscript.
        - Theology's heydey., No date (Box 51, Folder 51)
          9 leaves. Carbon typescript
    - Untitled, Beginning: The Arcade Post Office Land.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., No date (Box 51, Folder 40)
    - Victoria, B.C. - 8 p.m. 6/27/35.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., No date (Box 51, Folder 52)
    - When the Los Angeles Times was Dynamited. 1965 - 1966.
      - Manuscript.
        - Another typing., No date (Box 53, Folder 37)
          16 leaves. Typescript (carbon)
      - Manuscript material.
        - Correspondence., 1965 - 1966 (Box 53, Folder 35)
          6 items, 7 pcs
        - No title., No date (Box 53, Folder 36)
          16 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections
    - Where is Southern California. After 1954.
      - Manuscript.
        - Where is southern California?., No date (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Fiction, screen treatment.
    - Dan Benham.
      - Manuscript material.
        - WWR's notes., No date (Box 51, Folder 19)
          10 leaves. Holograph
        - Plan of a novel tentatively called Dan Benham., No date (Box 51, Folder 20)
          17 leaves total. Typescript with minor holograph corrections. In folder. Synopsis and 3 chapters
        - Plan of a novel tentatively called Dan Benham., No date (Box 51, Folder 21)
          17 leaves total. Typescript (carbon). With holograph corrections In folder
        - Plan of a novel tentatively called Dan Benham., No date (Box 51, Folder 22)
          17 leaves total. Typescript (carbon). In folder with WWR's note: 5/29/46, Dear Mr. Boardman: Here is the outline I mentioned. I shall be staying at the Barbizon Plaza all next week
      - Research material.
        - Newspaper clippings., No date (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Girl Who Didn't Date.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., No date (Box 51, Folder 17)
          [2310 S. Palmgrove Ave]. 8 leaves. Typescript
    - Haunted House.
      - Manuscript.
        - Haunted house., No date (Box 51, Folder 14)
          [2310 Palmgrove Ave]. 7 leaves. Typescript (carbon)
    - His Daughter.
      - Manuscript.
        - His daughter., No date (Box 51, Folder 13)
          [2001 Allston Way, Berkeley]. 1 leaf. Typescript
    - My Uncle Builds a House.
      - Manuscript.
        - My uncle builds a house., 1940 (Box 51, Folder 16)
          4 leaves. Typescript
    - Old California.
      - Manuscript.
        - Old California: a suggestion for a film story., No date (Box 51, Folder 26)
          4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections
      - Research material.
        - First draft continuity, "Wuthering Heights," etc., No date (Box 51, Folder 23)
          5 leaves. Evidently done to teach himself techniques of screenwriting
        - Newspaper clipping., 1935 (Box 51, Folder 24)
        - The horse race., No date (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Phrases Caught Midair at Magnin's.
      - Notes.
        - No title., No date (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Tides.
      - Manuscript.
        - Tides., No date (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Poetry.
    - Notes for Poems?.
      - Manuscript material.
        - Notes for poems?., No dates (Box 51, Folder 27)
          2 leaves. Holograph. One begins: The moon was brilliant, "; another: Throb / Propellers a dark whir / Roar
    - Poems Kept by WWR in an Envelope Postmarked 1930.
      - Manuscript.
        - Born., No date (Box 51, Folder 28)
          1 leaf. Typescript with holograph additions
        - Duty., No date (Box 51, Folder 29)
        - Red mesas., No date (Box 51, Folder 30)
        - Segment of the universe at New Years., No date (Box 51, Folder 31)
        - I invoke., No date (Box 51, Folder 32)
        - After April., No date (Box 51, Folder 33)
        - Docile dromedaries., No date (Box 51, Folder 34)
        - April., No date (Box 51, Folder 35)
        - Intrusion., No date (Box 51, Folder 36)
      - Manuscript material.
        - Notes., 1932? (Box 51, Folder 38)
        - Robinson, Mary W. Recompense., 1830 Aug (Box 51, Folder 39)
          2 leaves total. Holograph Typescript (carbon) and holograph
    - Poems Kept in an Envelope by WWR Postmarked 1930.
      - Manuscript.
        - You., No date (Box 51, Folder 37)
          2 cop. 2 leaves total. Typescript. and typescript (carbon)
  - Result of time in France, WWI.
    - A Permissionaire in Paris.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., No date (Box 51, Folder 6)
          [Army address in France]. 7 leaves. Typescript (carbon)
    - Destination - Brest.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., No date (Box 51, Folder 10)
          [2310 S. Palmgrove Ave]. 7 leaves. Typescript (carbon). Carbon typescript
    - Morning Near Chatenay.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., 1918 (Box 51, Folder 4)
          1 leaf. Holograph. With this: sketch map
    - The Calvary of Pontcharteau.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., No date (Box 51, Folder 8)
          [715 S. Hope St]. 5 leaves. Typescript
      - Research material.
        - No title., No date (Box 51, Folder 7)
          6 postcards with holograph notes verso
    - The Three - Day Trip to Paree.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., No date (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Untitled Beginning: About Noon on Monday.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., No date (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Untitled, Beginning: The Great Bay May be Reached from St. Malo.
      - Manuscript.
        - No title., 1919 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Unpublished revisions of published works.
    - Land in California.
      - Editorial material.
        - Correspondence., 1964 May - Jun, 1965 Jan and Mar (Box 52, Folder 1)
          8 items, 8 pcs. Also: 1 leaf holograph notes
        - Correspondence., 1969 Apr - Aug, Dec; 1971 Nov - Dec; 1972 Feb (Box 52, Folder 2)
          35 items, 82 pcs. Includes three snapshots. With Mildred S. Ligda
        - Enclosures to the Ligda correspondence., No date (Box 52, Folder 3)
          Includes Hermes Publications, photocopies of correspondence, cost estimates, etc
        - [Untitled advertising statement about WWR's qualifications, written by himself]., No date (Box 52, Folder 4)
          2 leaves. Carbon typescript with minor holograph corrections. Also 1 leaf of WWR's notes
        - Legal agreement with Ligda., 1969 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Manuscript material.
        - Comments on various chapters., No date (Box 52, Folder 8)
          16 leaves. Holograph
      - Research material.
        - Carbon of letter from WWR., No date (Box 52, Folder 6)
        - Magazine clipping., 1969 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Ranchos of California.
      - Editorial material.
        - Correspondence., 1956 Jun - Jul (Box 52, Folder 12)
          2 items, 2 pcs. About republication by David Magee
        - Correspondence., 1965 Mar - Apr, Jun - Jul (Box 52, Folder 13)
          9 items, 9 pcs. About republication by Lane Publications and / or Ward Ritchie
        - Correspondence., 1956 Jan (Box 52, Folder 14)
          2 items, 2 pcs. About republication by Title Insurance and Trust
      - Manuscript material.
        - Notes on structure, etc., No date (Box 52, Folder 18)
        - Notes on structure, titles, etc., No date (Box 52, Folder 19)
          4 leaves. Typescript with varying holograph additions
        - Various outlines. Kingdoms for the asking - story of the Spanish and Mexican ranchos of California., No date (Box 52, Folder 20)
          1 leaf. 2 leaves. Typescript, marked "superseded" in WWR's hand. HELP????????
        - II. The rancho map of California; and III. Kingdoms for the asking., No date (Box 52, Folder 21)
          10 leaves numbered [6] - 15. 6 leaves numbered [13] - 18. Carbon typescript
        - I. Rancho heritage; and II. The rancho map of California., No date (Box 52, Folder 22)
          12 leaves. Carbon typescript with holograph corrections
      - Research material.
        - Correspondence., 1955 Jun - Jul, 1956 Jan - Feb (Box 52, Folder 14)
          9 items, 10 pcs
        - WWR's notes., No date (Box 52, Folder 15)
        - Typed material., No date (Box 52, Folder 16)
        - Newspaper clippings., 1950, 1959, 1960, 1965 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Writing projects.
    - Main Street Panels [Murals].
      - Outline.
        - Suggested titles for Main Street panels., No date (Box 55, Folder 14)
          1 leaf. Typescript (carbon). With extensive holograph corrections
        - Orange County rancho murals - 20 suggested panels., 1958 Jul (Box 55, Folder 16)
          4 leaves. Typescript (carbon). with holograph additions. Two versions of suggestions? Sections called: A and B
    - California Motion Pictures / Hollywood Bibliography / Alcaldes.
      - Editorial material.
        - Letter., 1971 Feb (Box 55, Folder 31)
          1 item, 1 pc. From Glen Dawson requesting manuscript from WWR on above topics
    - California: A Picture History. No Date.
      - Outline.
        - Also notes on printing cost., No date (Box 55, Folder 33)
          2 leaves total. Typescript. Section outline for a book to be developed and presented in the manner of "Panorama" and to be entitled California - a picture history
    - Clearing Muddy Waters. 1969.
      - Note.
        - WWR's notation of title and subject., No date (Box 55, Folder 30)
    - Counties of California. 1960.
      - Editorial material.
        - Correspondence., 1960 Jan (Box 55, Folder 19)
          2 items., 3 pcs
    - Hollywood Museum.
      - Manuscript material.
        - [Outline]., 1965 Aug 14 (Box 55, Folder 23)
          2 leaves. Typescript with holograph additions
        - The state of the museum in its sixth year., 1965 Aug 17 (Box 55, Folder 24)
          [1], 4 leaves. Typescript (carbon). Note on cover leaf in WWR's hand: superseded in part expanded. Last leaf has signature block for Sol Lesser
      - Research material.
        - WWR's notes., No date (Box 55, Folder 20)
          9 leaves. Holograph
        - Magazine clippings., 1964 - 1965 (Box 55, Folder 21)
        - Newspaper clippings., 1965 (Box 55, Folder 22)
    - Los Angeles County Book. 1960.
      - Editorial material.
        - Carbon of letter from WWR., 1959 Feb (Box 55, Folder 17)
      - Outline.
        - Suggested outline for a book on Los Angeles County., 1959 Jan (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - Miniature Books About Santa Barbara.
      - Editorial material.
        - Correspondence., 1967 Mar, Aug - Sep, and no date (Box 55, Folder 25)
        - WWR's notes., No date (Box 55, Folder 26)
        - [California dichos]., No date (Box 55, Folder 27)
          [9] leaves. Typescript with holograph initial letters. Evidently those WWR felt should not be printed
        - Sample of size of miniature book and notes., No date (Box 55, Folder 28)
        - Material about Santa Barbara Mission archive., 1966 - 1967, and no date (Box 55, Folder 29)
    - Pacific Coast Picture History. 1954.
      - Research material.
        - A suggestion that looks to the future of the Pacific coast., 1954 Dec (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Pageant: A Pictorial History of Los Angeles County. No Date.
      - Pre manuscript material.
        - WWR's notation of title., No date (Box 55, Folder 32)
    - Palm Springs. No Date.
      - Research material.
        - WWR's notes., No date (Box 55, Folder 34)
          23 leaves in notepad [also 3 blank leaves]. Holograph
    - Suggested Titles for Main Street Panels [Murals].
      - Editorial material.
        - Correspondence., 1958 Aug - Sep (Box 55, Folder 12)
      - Outline.
        - Suggested panels for Main Street murals., 1958 Jul (Box 55, Folder 15)
      - Research material.
        - Printed material., 1949 Autumn and no date (Box 55, Folder 13)
          Touring topics, Los Angeles County Museum quarterly
    - Various.
      - Research material?.
        - WWR's notes., No date (Box 55, Folder 36)
          7 leaves. Holograph. Jottings, etc. Unclear to what they pertain. One is: Calif counties with pictures, old and new --
    - Westchester Booklet. CA. 1950 - 1953.
      - Research material.
        - WWR's notes., No date (Box 55, Folder 1)
          12 leaves. Holograph. Includes notes on property titles since Daniel Freeman. One leaf is headed: Westchester Booklet
        - [Fred Marlow interview] 2 cop., 1950 Jan 25 (Box 55, Folder 2)
          6 leaves total. Typescript. Typescript with holograph notations. Another copy. Carbon typescript
        - [Charles M. Crawford interview]., No date (Box 55, Folder 3)
          2 cop. 6 leaves total. Typescript (carbon). Carbon typescript with holograph notations. Another copy. Carbon typescript
        - [Henry V. Wall interview]. 2 cop., No date (Box 55, Folder 4)
          4 leaves total. Typescript. Typescript with holograph notations and additions. Another copy. Carbon typescript
        - Excerpt from Carey Mcwilliams. 2 cop., No date (Box 55, Folder 5)
          12 leaves total. Typescript. Typescript. Carbon typescript. Unique community planning follows expansion of defense industries; by Henry V. Wall. Typescript
        - Wall. Unique community planning [copy]., 1942 (Box 55, Folder 6)
          2 leaves. Typescript with WWR's holograph notes
        - Map of Los Angeles and adjacent cities., 1948 Feb (Box 55, Folder 7)
          Section of Westchester outlined in holograph by WWR with additional notes
        - Printed material., ca. 1953 and no date (Box 55, Folder 8)
          Also: Pictorial souvenir of Westchester; courtesy, Marlow-Burns
        - Printed material about real estate and tract homes., No date (Box 55, Folder 9)
        - Newspaper clippings., 1950 Jan, 1950 Feb 2, 1951Mar 28, 1953 Jun, 1963 Apr (Box 55, Folder 10)
          Copies of: Westchester News - advertiser; Los Angeles Evening Herald Express - special edition
    - Westlake History. No Date.
      - Research material.
        - WWR's notes., No date (Box 55, Folder 35)